Tyrone Sanderson

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Personal Info

Location:

New York, NY

Contact:

(646) 427-6375

sandersontyrone77@gmail.com

Professional Links

Linkedin

Technical Skills

AWS(EKS, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda, Cloudwatch, IAM))

AWS Networking

Jira

Github | Git

Linux Administration

Bash Scripting

Python Scripting

Jenkins

Terraform

Docker

Kubernetes

Datadog

JavaScript

OPNsense, Wireshark, NMap, Sysinternals, Suricata, Snort, Nessus

Windows Server 16

Ansible

Windows 10

macOS

VMware(Fusion, Workstation, ESXI)

Jmeter

Professional Summary

Certified Linux Administrator and Network Security Professional with 5 years of experience in networking, cloud technologies, and DevOps methodologies. I specialize in leading technical and non-technical teams through complex projects and applying advanced technical knowledge to develop and enhance real-world IT infrastructures.

Certifications

CompTIA A | CompTIA Network+ | CompTIA Linux+ | CompTIA CYSA

Employment History

Lead Technical Instructor/Curriculum Developer, Kura Labs, New York
APRIL 2022 – DECEMBER 2023

Lead DevOps Instructor

- Directed daily live training sessions for cohorts of up to 30 adults, focusing
 on constructing robust AWS infrastructures, developing resilient application
 environments, and architecting efficient CI/CD pipelines.
- Administered mock technical interviews to prepare cohorts for competitive FinTech job interviews.
- Conducted practical, hands-on demonstrations on:
 - Managing software using the Advanced Package Tool (APT), troubleshooting network issues via CLI, and monitoring server processes and resources.
 - Implementing Jenkins for a Flask application build, performing application testing (unit and end-to-end testing), and deploying to AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
 - Utilizing Git and GitHub for collaboration, version control, and application rollbacks.
 - Creating AWS Virtual Private Clouds (VPC) manually via the AWS Console and programmatically using Terraform.
 - Building, testing, and tagging Flasks application images with Docker, including deploying to AWS Elastic Container Service (ECS) for container orchestration.
 - Deploying a 3-tier React frontend and Django backend application using Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS).
- Facilitated system design workshops using Draw.io
- Upheld the integrity of the company's GitHub repository, ensuring meticulous management of deployment projects and educational assignments

Curriculum Developer

- Managed an AWS Organization account, establishing permissions for students, monitoring budget alerts, and overseeing account creation processes.
- Collaboratively designed a comprehensive 6-month DevOps curriculum with input from DevOps Engineers. The curriculum encompassed key areas including Linux Administration, Git and GitHub workflows, AWS services, Networking Fundamentals, Datadog, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, and Kubernetes.

- Created 2O diverse application deployment projects designed to provide hands-on experience in real world scenarios. Integrating the following tools: Jenkins, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, ECS, EKS, EC2, CloudFront, RDS, Route 53, Auto Scaling, Application Load Balancer (ALB), Kubernetes, Datadog, Cloudwatch, and Docker. These projects were designed to provide hands-on experience in real-world scenarios.
- Devised 4 intricate Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) scenarios using JMeter,
 challenging students to apply their skills in simulated high-stakes environments.

Technical Instructor/System Administrator, Per Scholas, New York

JULY 2019 - MARCH 2022

Cyber Security Instructor

- Delivered comprehensive training in network security, device hardening, NIST framework, data security standards (including PCI DSS, PII, HIPAA, and FISMA).
- Demonstrated the configuration and use of OPNsense for firewall setups, rule definition, web proxy, network monitoring, antivirus (ClamAV), and intrusion detection and prevention systems (Suricata, Snort) for deep packet inspection.
- Conducted vulnerability assessments using Nessus on different operating systems (MacOS, Windows, Linux) to identify and analyze security vulnerabilities.

Network Support Instructor

- Educated students on network fundamentals and components such as DNS,
 DHCP, IP addresses, firewalls, network cables, routers, and switches.
- Demonstrated network troubleshooting techniques using the Windows CMD,
 Linux terminal, Wireshark, cable finders, and cable testers.

System Administration

- Managed a technical lab with 20 Dell desktops running Windows 10 and 2 servers on VMware ESXi (One server with a PFsense virtual machine and the second server with Windows Server 2016 VM and Security Onion VM).
- Conducted monthly vulnerability scans to ensure laboratory PCs and servers were not exposed to critical vulnerabilities
- Installed and supervised the lab's Unified Threat Manager (PFsense) to monitor and safeguard network traffic.

Courses

System Administration, Per Scholas

DECEMBER 2018 - FEBRUARY 2019

Education

High School Diploma, New Design High School, New York

SEPTEMBER 2002 - JUNE 2006